gshiftlabs.com 2017-06-27

# Privacy Policy | gShift SEO Software

**gShift Labs Inc. respects the privacy of visitors to this website.**

Your personal information is only collected, used and disclosed by gShift Labs in accordance with this Privacy Policy. gShift Labs reserves the right to amend this policy at any time and for any reason. An up-to-date policy will always appear on this Website.

Personal information is any information about an identifiable individual, such as contact details and usernames/passwords. Aggregate information that cannot be associated with a specific individual, such as the number of blog subscribers we serve, is not personal information. You can visit gshiftlabs.com on the Internet without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself. We only collect your personal information when you specifically and knowingly provide it on our Website.

If you do provide any of the information asked for on this site, you are expressly consenting to and have knowledge of the collection, use and disclosure of this information, as identified in this Privacy Policy.

#### 1\. WHO IS ACCOUNTABLE?

gShift Labs Inc. takes full responsibility for the management and confidentiality of the personal information it collects. If you have any concerns about this policy, or feel that gShift Labs is not abiding by this policy, please write or send an email message to:

**Privacy Policy Information**  
gShift Labs Inc.  
85 Bayfield Street, Suite 202  
Barrie, ON, Canada  
L4M 6G2

To email gShift Labs: Please complete the [Contact Us](http://www.gshiftlabs.com/about-us/contact/ "Contact Info") Form. Your concerns will be addressed in a timely manner.

gShift Labs provides the Web hosting and technical support services of this Website. Personal information about our blog subscribers resides on gShift Labs’ managed servers. This data is only accessed by gShift Labs if required in order to provide technical support, and is kept strictly confidential.

#### 2\. INFORMATION COLLECTED AND USED

gShift Labs collects and uses your information only for the following purposes:

  * to provide you with our blog and news alert services;
  * to respond to your requests for further information about our WPO software system Web Presence Optimizer™ and SEO reports;
  * to register individuals to gShift Labs’ User Group or events;
  * to provide gShift Labs’ clients and partners with reliable and quality support; and
  * to meet legal and regulatory requirements.

When subscribing to gShift Labs’ blog, you must provide us with your email address in order for us to send our blog posts to you on a monthly basis.

If you’re filling out any of the Contact Us forms, and you want to find out more about our SEO software system, we also require you to provide us with your name in order for us to personalize our communications with you. If you’re filling out any one of the Contact Sales, Free Trial Qualification or Agency Program forms we further require your phone number so we may contact you directly to discuss your Web presence optimization needs in person.

By submitting your information to gShift Labs we may contact you periodically regarding future promotions, product launches, special events and other valuable company information. In all of our communications you will always be able to opt out at any time.

#### 3\. INFORMATION THAT DOES NOT IDENTIFY YOU

gShift Labs collects certain technical information from your computer’s Web browser or Internet device when you visit [www.gshiftlabs.com](http://www.gshiftlabs.com/ "SEO Software for Agencies & Marketers | gShift Labs") on the Internet. This information includes the amount of time spent on the site by a visitor with a unique Internet identifier, the pages visited and returned to, the operating system, and Web browser used, the referring Website and any keywords used to find our site on a search Website. These server logs do not contain any personal information and can only be accessed by gShift Labs. Server log files are used solely to track visits to our Website and improve the experience, content and layout of our site. gShift Labs makes no attempt to link this traffic information to the individuals visiting our Website.

gShift Labs has also implemented Remarketing with Google Analytics for Display Advertising online. gShift Labs and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to [www.gshiftlabs.com](http://www.gshiftlabs.com/ "SEO Software for Agencies & Marketers | gShift Labs"). As a result, gShift’s ads are shown on websites across the Internet. Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the [Ads Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/?hl=en&sig=ACi0TCh-h3CrkyQsDKfl9v4Q8eGMzDy9FxMOPB4TQOFbk9Nt8jCqpgV4EMX9eZ3Se2PA4m4X7uXv0TFzOhjfxTEmwkoJnaOc7LAfPv90VEsqZTKpHy4Eero5cBr_gyl9cMyhBXZdc4zoSrWtkggu2KOMY6Y_2u53EgAC2EYyiLSMMITsU_zxwAA "Ads Preferences Manager | Google").

Anyone can browse gShift Labs’ Website with cookies turned off, but if you’re a gShift Labs agency partner or client and you wish to log in to your gShift Labs account, you must accept cookies. A cookie/session variable is assigned to you when you log in, and placed on your computer for programming purposes only. This is a session cookie that uniquely identifies you as you move from page to page inside the Extranet area. It ensures that you have properly logged in and that your organization’s personal information is only accessible to you. The cookie is destroyed as soon as you close your browser and is never redirected to any other servers.

#### 4\. DISCLOSURE AND RETENTION OF YOUR INFORMATION

We do not sell, trade or share any of your personal information with any other third-party organizations. We will release personal information when we believe such release is appropriate in order to comply with the law; for example, if we receive a subpoena or court order.

If you have subscribed to gShift Labs’ blog, your email address and other information that you have provided to us is kept as long as you are a subscriber.

In the event that you choose to unsubscribe from gShift Labs’ blog and news alerts, your information will be immediately deleted from our database, and you will no longer receive any information from gShift Labs. However, residual information about you may remain in backup files temporarily. Backups of our blog subscriber databases occur nightly and weekly. Weekly backups are overwritten such that information older than one week is permanently destroyed and irretrievable.

#### 5\. ACCURACY OF THE INFORMATION AND ACCESS TO IT

gShift Labs relies exclusively on the information provided by its Website users and subscribers, and will not seek independent verification of any of the information supplied. Thus, a blog subscriber, or someone awaiting a response to a request for information is responsible for letting gShift Labs know if their email address has changed. Personal information can be viewed and corrected directly by gShift clients or agency partners once they have logged in.

#### 6\. HOW IS THE INFORMATION KEPT SAFE?

The server is protected by an enterprise firewall that is immediately updated when new patches and fixes are released.

Information entered anywhere else on our Website is transmitted to the gShift Labs server unencrypted, using standard Internet protocol (HTTP). You should be aware of the inherent risks of interception when communicating with others online. Visit gShift Labs’ [Terms and Conditions](http://www.gshiftlabs.com/terms-and-conditions/ "Terms and Conditions") for further details. Your email messages to gShift Labs are kept secure once they reach us – software is installed on all computers at gShift Labs’ location that prevents viruses and malicious activity.

_By providing you with this Privacy Policy, gShift Labs is pledging its continued commitment to protecting the information we collect. We regularly review our information-handling practices to ensure that we are abiding by this policy._
